{"data":[{"question":"I said to him, \" If I were in your place, I would do otherwise.\" \n= I told him that if I ___ in his place, I ___ otherwise.","a":"were, would do","b":"had been, would do","c":"were, would have done","d":"had been, would have done","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Unreal condition sentence: tense is not changed in indirect speech","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"I said to him, \" Please go \" \n= I ___ him to go.","a":"pleased","b":"said to","c":"ordered","d":"begged","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Please- beg ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"Tom suggested to us that we should play soccer from then on. \n= Tom said to us, \" ___ play soccer from now on.\"","a":"We should","b":"We must","c":"Let's","d":"We will","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Suggest - Let's","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"The doctor advised Mary not to overwork herself.\n\n= The doctor said to Mary, \" You _________ overwork yourself.\"","a":"must not","b":"had better not","c":"don't have to","d":"don't","answer":"2","explain":"\n\n- Advise-> should do, had better do something","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"He said, \" I shall be eighteen next year.\" \n= He said that he. ___ be eighteen ___.","a":"would, the next year","b":"would, next year","c":"will, next year","d":"shall, the next year","answer":"1","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original\u00a0\n+ Next year (from now): already determined= use \"The\"","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"The teacher said, \" The Civil War broke out in 1861\" \n= The teacher said that the Civil War ___ out in 1861.","a":"breaks","b":"broke","c":"has broken","d":"had broken","answer":"2","explain":"\n- If reporting a general truth the present tense will be retained or even the future tense can be used ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"He said to me, \" I have lost my pen. May I use yours?\" \n= He told me he had lost his pen, and _________ he might use mine.","a":"that","b":"if","c":"asked me if","d":"questioned if","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Interrogative - indirect speech: uses \"ask\" as reported word ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"She said, \" Y e s .\"\n\n= She answered in the ___.","a":"yes","b":"right","c":"agreement","d":"affirmative","answer":"4","explain":"\n\n- \"Yes\" means \"agree\/affirmative\"","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"She said, \"Will you go there? \" I said, \" Yes.\"\n\n= She asked if I would go there, and I said ___.","a":"yes","b":"in affirmative","c":"I wouldn't","d":"I would","answer":"4","explain":"\n\n-\" Yes\" = Agree to go there\n\n- I would= I would to go there","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"She said, \" May God bless this baby of mine !\n\n= She ___ that God might bless her baby.","a":"wished","b":"hoped","c":"prayed","d":"suggested","answer":"3","explain":"\n\n- Use \"Pray\" for \"God\"","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"}]}